到处都是水
There was water everywhere.
场面可惨了
It was such a mess.
太倒霉了  那你得暂离你公寓多久
That stinks. How long are you out of the apartment?
大约五周吧
About five weeks.
你有损失什么值钱财物吗
Ugh! Did you lose anything valuable?
那个管道是在我衣柜上方
Well, the pipe was over my closet,
所以我所有衣物全泡汤了
so all my clothes are gone.
那就是没损失  不错
Oh, so nothing. Great.
他们知道管道为何爆裂吗
Do they know why the pipe burst?
他们没说
They didn't say.
那些使用了
Buildings that have a combination
铜管与镀锌钢管的建筑
of copper and galvanized steel
易受水中离子的电迁移率
are susceptible to pinholes and corrosion
而导致破洞跟腐蚀
caused by the mobility of ions in the water.
像我这样头常被恶霸塞进马桶里的人
Can't have your head shoved in a toilet as much as I did
难免会学到一点管道方面的知识
and not pick up a few things about plumbing.
如果你需要地方暂住  你可以来跟我们住啊
Well, if you need a place to crash, you can stay with us.
-真的吗  -当然啦
- Really? - Of course.
你可以睡莱纳德的房间  我跟他住我家
You can stay in Leonard's room, and we'll stay at my place.
你确定不会造成你们不便吗
You're sure that's not an inconvenience?
不会  完全不会
No, not at all.
而且我们跟谢尔顿住
And we live with Sheldon,
"不便"这个词与我们早已是路人
so the word "inconvenience" has really lost all meaning.
所以严格上来说  我要跟我男朋友同居了吗
So, technically, I'd be moving in with my boyfriend?
算吧
I guess so.
而我也终于可以单独跟我丈夫同住了
I'd finally get to live alone with my husband.
天啊  关系迈进了一大步啊
Oh, my, this is a big step.
对于咱俩来说  是朝着正确方向迈进
For two of us, it's in the right direction.
你们为啥都笑得跟傻子一样
Why are you all smiling like crazy people?
与我女友住同一屋檐下吗
Cohabitation with my girlfriend?
这可是件大事啊
That's a great deal to process.
只是同住五周而已
It's only for five weeks.
而且我们俩就在对门而已
Yeah, and we'll be right across the hall.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我也不知道
I don't know.
万一同住之后浪漫的火花就没了呢
What if living together kills the romance?
你们俩滚过足足一次床单呢
Okay, you guys had sex one whole time.
没有任何事能灭了那"大火"
Nothing can put out a fire like that.
但当我们互相看到了私底下最私密的一面呢
Yeah, but what happens when we each get a peek behind the curtain?
她还没见过我没刮胡子的样子呢
I mean, she's never even seen me unshaven.
你昨天刚刮过了
You just shaved yesterday.
你接下来三个月都没有这问题
You're good for three months.
谢尔顿  我能理解你的考量
Sheldon, I understand your apprehension,
但请让我用科学家角度说服你
but let me appeal to the scientist in you.
同住的时间是五周
Given the five-week end date,
这长度正好适合我们来实验彼此契合度
isn't it the perfect opportunity to consider this an experiment
并搜集数据不是吗
and collect data on our compatibility?
少用这种撩人的话来套路我
Don't try luring me in with sexy talk.
这么说吧
Okay.
电视剧《星际旅行：初代》
Star Trek: The Original Series.
进取号开始了一个五年期探索新世界的任务
The Enterprise was on a five-year mission to explore new worlds.
把这件事
Think of this as your
也想成是你个人的五周期任务嘛
personal five-week mission to do the same.
你想用撩人的话来套路我  就得像他这样
If you want to lure me in with sexy talk, that's how you do it.
你有毛好骄傲啊
Don't be proud of that.
所以你同意了吗
So, is that a yes?
还没呢  我...
Not yet. I...
我如何能确定我是跟艾米相住愉快
How will I learn if I'm comfortable living with Amy
还是因为只是在自己家里待得舒服呢
or just comfortable because I'm in my own apartment?
如果要让这个实验有效
Now, if this experiment is going to be valid,
我建议我跟她得住在中立环境
I suggest a neutral environment.
那你们要住哪去
Well, where would you go?
理想来说  在新墨西哥州的
Well, ideally, an enclosed,
一个封闭式  能自给自足的生态馆里
self-sustaining biodome in New Mexico.
在那里我们吃用我们排泄物施肥的农作物
Where we would eat crops fertilized with our own waste.
同住怕不浪漫  吃屎就浪漫了吗
And you were worried about the romance.
等等  那你们怎么不直接住去我家
Wait. Why don't you guys stay across the hall,
然后我跟莱纳德住这里
and we will live here?
有意思
Interesting.
如果我把寝宫移到了对门
If my official residence were across the hall,
那我回来这里需不需要敲门呢
I wonder if I'd need to knock every time I came over here.
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
要不你就干脆别回来了
Maybe just don't come over.
从过去经验来看  我很不适应改变
Historically, I don't do well with change.
也不会有那么糟啦
Okay, it won't be that bad.
你不在的时候  我们也不会去坐你的专座
We wouldn't even sit in your spot while you're gone.
大胆刁民  你当然不敢
You're darn right, you wouldn't.
无论我在哪里  这里永远都是我的专座
No matter where I am, this will always be my spot.
就像是那些外国大使馆
Like an embassy in a foreign country,
这座位永远是我屁股不可分割的一部分
this seat is the sovereign soil of my bottom.
就点头陪笑就对了  他就要走了
Just nod and smile. He's almost gone.
谢尔顿  你觉得呢
Sheldon, what do you think?
好吧  我同意
Very well. I'm on board.
-真的吗  -真的
- Seriously? - Yes.
我接受这个五周的任务
I accept this five-week mission
跟我的女朋友分享同一居住空间
to share a living space with my girlfriend.
好兴奋啊
Oh. This is so exciting.
但跟《原初系列》一样
Well, now, don't be surprised if, like Star Trek,
三季就砍的话  也别太惊讶
it's canceled in three.
不得不说  我对你的妇产科医生挺满意
I have to say, I am happy with your OBGYN.
那就好  因为那医生也很满意
Cool. 'Cause she says you're doing a great job as
你这位"明明不用每次都跟来的怪朋友"
"Weird friend who doesn't have to be at every appointment."
我父亲是一名妇科医生  我能帮得上忙嘛
I'm the son of a gynecologist. I could be helpful.
你想帮忙的话就不要跟我说
It would help if you stopped telling me
我的子宫颈长得很标准了
I have a textbook cervix.
有礼貌的回答应该是"谢谢你注意到"
The polite response is, "Thank you for noticing."
再让我看一次B超图
Let me see the sonogram again.
这个小灰团看起来就是一个漂亮宝宝
Oh, yeah, that's a good-looking baby for a little gray blob.
我们可以给他取名团仔
Yeah, we could name him Blobert.
如果是女孩怎么办
What if it's a girl?
灰灰
Bloberta.
或者是灰妞
Or Blobbi with an "I."
我们不问性别是不是太傻了
Are we being silly not finding out the sex?
我也正在想这事呢
Yeah, I was just thinking the same thing.
如果你们愿意  你们现在就能知道
If you want, you can find out right now.
医生今天已经下班了  算了
The doctor's gone for the day, so it doesn't matter.
有人可是在档案里看到了哦
Well, somebody else knows because they saw it in the folder.
你偷看了我们的档案吗
You looked in our folder?!
我不小心看到的
It was an accident.
医生就这样随随便便把档案放在她桌子上
The doctor left the folder out on her desk.
于是我就看了  怪我咯
It's not my fault I opened it and looked.
所以你知道孩子的性别  我们却一无所知
So you know the sex of our baby, and we don't?!
你们可以投硬币  猜对的机会高达5成
Flip a coin. You got a fifty-fifty shot.
-真不敢相信  -你妹的  拉杰
- It's unbelievable. - God, Raj.
咋了  这又不是什么问题
What? This is not a problem, okay?
你们如果不想知道  我不告诉你们就好啦
If you don't want to know, I don't have to tell you.
我们不想让你知道
We don't want you to know!
好吧  这就的确是个问题
Okay, well, that's a problem.
你愿意尝试和艾米同居  我可为你自豪了
You know, I'm very proud of you for trying to live with Amy.
谢谢
Oh. Thank you.
其实最理想方式是
Of course, the ideal way to conduct this experiment
使用四组完全一样的谢尔顿和艾米来做实验
would be with four pairs of identical Sheldons and Amys.
第一组不是恋爱关系  也不同居
One pair that was neither dating nor living together.
第二组是恋爱关系  但不同居
One pair that was dating but not living together.
第三组同居  但不是恋爱关系
One pair that was living together but not dating.
最后  第四组
And then, of course, one pair
既是恋爱关系又同居在一起
that was living together and dating.
不过  如果真有这么多的谢尔顿
Although, with that many Sheldons,
大家早就玩得忘乎所以  忘掉实验的事了
it'd be such a party, we'd never get anything done.
真是个萌萌的小故事啊
That was a cute story.
那个...
So, um...
你之前想问我什么来着
What did you want to ask me?
你有过和恋人同居的经验
Well, you've lived with your significant other for some time.
我希望这次实验可以顺利进行
I would like this experiment to go well.
你有什么好建议吗
Are there any insights you can share?
最重要的一点  如果她的室友是个疯子
Well, the biggie is, if she has an insane roommate,
不要犹豫  立刻把那室友扫地出门
kick him out as soon as possible.
在你出现之前  莱纳德和我可幸福美满了
You know, Leonard and I were very happy before you came along.
你和谢尔顿做了这么久的室友
You've been roommates with Sheldon forever.
有什么经验之谈吗
Do you have any advice?
我正努力寻找一个
I'm trying to think of an answer
不会让你不敢搬进来的答案
that won't stop you from doing this.
虽然这是老生常谈了
I know it sounds like a cliche
但退一步真的会海阔天空
but compromise is key.
不要把皮带留在地板上
Never leave a belt on the floor.
在晚上看起来特别像蛇
At night, they look like snakes.
从小事做起  早上把咖啡送到她床上去
Do little things, like bring her a cup of coffee in bed.
口袋里时刻备有巧克力豆
Keep M&M'S in your pocket
以防你们俩遇到排长队的时候
in case you have to wait in a long line.
你们每天都要见好多次面
You're gonna be seeing each other a lot,
所以要尊重各自的私人空间
so respect each other's personal space.
他特别容易受惊吓  照相千万别开闪光灯
He startles easily, so, please, no flash photography.
你这次带了几条内裤
How many pairs of underwear did you pack for the move?
我不知道  我没数
I don't know. I didn't count.
真是白面秀才遇上了邋遢兵
You truly are the Goofus to my Gallant.
对  兵是我  听我说
That's me.  Listen,
你和我要睡在一张床上了
you and I are gonna be sharing a bed.
这件事对于我俩都是头一次
You know, this is uncharted territory for both of us.
你对此有何感想
How are you feeling about that?
非常兴奋  有些疑虑
Oh, excited, concerned,
还有点害怕
a little scared.
就跟我在迪斯尼太空山排队时的心情一模一样
All the same emotions I feel in line at Space Mountain.
如果你是为睡觉的问题而困扰的话
Well, if you're nervous about the sleeping arrangements,
也许我们应该好好谈一谈
maybe we should talk about it.
好呀
Okay.
谈吧
Talk.
我猜你的疑虑之一
Well, I imagine one of your concerns
应该是担心会需要做爱吧
might be coital expectations.
也不来点前戏  直捣黄龙啊
Wow, no foreplay or anything, just right to it.
我明白这次实验对你来说是
Look, I know this experiment
迈出舒适圈的一大步
is a big step outside of your comfort zone.
所以我们不如先暂缓发生性关系
So why don't we take being physical off the table
留到后面
and maybe later on,
等彼此适应下来  再提这个话题
once we're more settled in, we can revisit it.
你对此真的没意见吗
You're really okay with that?
我也从来没和别人同居过
I've never lived with someone, either.
这对我来说也是大挑战
This is a lot for me, too.
听你这么说我心里就轻松了
This is such a relief.
说真的  要不是怕你会欲火焚身
Honestly, if it didn't get you all worked up,
我都想吻你来谢你
I'd kiss you right now.
好决定
Good call.
在看到你的《少年泰坦》卡通内裤后
Seeing your Teen Titans underwear
我的确是"性致高昂"
really got my motor running.
我懂你  这种产品就不该卖给孩子
I know. They probably shouldn't sell those to children.
钥匙给你
Well, here's your key.
谢谢
Thank you.
好好享受公寓里二人世界吧
Enjoy having the place to yourselves.
你们也好好享受
You enjoy your mission to boldly go
这段从未有人涉足过的伟大任务吧
where no man has gone before.
那是佩妮的卧室
It's Penny's bedroom.
涉足其中的男人数不胜数
Plenty of men have gone before.
好了好了  不要搞得这么情绪化
Now, now, there's no need to make this emotional.
我们走吧
Shall we?
看来要就此别过了
I guess this is it.
祝你们住得高兴
You guys have fun.
你也是
You, too.
别忘了
Oh, don't forget.
周二得换空气净化器滤网
Tuesday the air filters need to be changed.
记得  你已经写我手上了
Yeah, you wrote it on my hand.
还有每隔一天
Oh, and every other day,
检查牛油果盆栽的水位
check the water level on the avocado pit.
我来负责
I'm on it.
十五年后  我们可以一起做牛油果酱
15 years from now, we'll make guacamole together.
莱纳德  别撩我让我走
Leonard, please, let me go.
走了  谢尔顿
Come on, Sheldon.
再见
Oh. Bye.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
就这样
Well, that's it.
接下来的五个星期里  我们要正式同居
For the next five weeks, we are officially living together.
实验就此开始
I guess the experiment begins.
-我们成功了  -好棒
- We did it! - Yeah!
你比较想睡在床的哪一侧
Which side of the bed would you prefer?
我无所谓  你选吧
Doesn't matter to me. Your choice.
不行不行  我们现在同居了  一切平等
No, no, we're living together now-- everything's equal.
其实我知道我的控制欲稍强一点
You know? I know that I have a tendency to be controlling,
所以我希望由你来选择
so I would rather you choose.
谢尔顿  你的好意我心领了
Well, Sheldon, I really appreciate that,
但这些事对你来说更为重要
but these things mean more to you than they do to me,
所以你想怎样都行
so whatever you want.
这明显就不是我想怎样都行
Well, clearly, it's not whatever I want,
因为我想要你来做选择
because what I want is for you to make this decision,
而你拒绝了
and you refuse to do that.
我不是拒绝
Well, I'm not refusing.
只是想考虑周全而已
I'm just trying to be considerate.
就像你叫我买那双
Like when you let me get those shoes
鞋底带着轮子的鞋
with the wheels on the bottom,
然后眼睁睁看着我滚入车流之中吗
and then watched me roll right into traffic?
-谢尔顿  你就赶紧选行不行  -好吧
- Sheldon, will you please just pick a side? - Fine.
好的  在这一侧
Okay. Now, on this side,
一旦发生意外  我离出口更近
I am closer to the exit in case of emergency.
很好  你就睡这侧
Great. That's your side.
可一旦有人进屋袭击  我离他也更近
No, but I'm also closer to the entrance in case of attack.
行  那我就睡那侧
Okay, I'll take that side.
可话说回来  有人来袭击的几率又能有多大
Ah, then again, what are the odds of someone attacking me?
急速增长中
Rising rapidly.
而在这一侧  方便我去卫生间
Now, this side offers me proximity to the bathroom,
但也离窗户较近
but I am closer to the window
怪叔叔可以偷看我睡觉觉
where perverts can watch me sleep.
好的
Okay.
那这样有没有好点
What if we do this?
这样也行
I suppose that works.
很好
Great.
不过我现在开始担心有人藏在窗帘后面了
Although now I'm kind of worried someone's hiding behind those drapes.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
医生知道孩子的性别
The doctor knows what the baby is,
超声波的技术人员知道  拉杰知道
the ultrasound tech knows, Raj knows,
他在的《实习医生格蕾》线上粉丝群友可能也知道
his Grey's Anatomy online fan group probably knows.
我们不知道会不会很奇怪
Is it weird we don't?
不知道
I don't know.
也许最后的惊喜会让它更有意思
Maybe the surprise will make it more fun.
就像魔术一样
Like magic tricks.
还记得我跟你揭秘了无穷尽手帕魔术时
Remember how disappointed you were
你当时有多失望吗
when I explained the never-ending hanky?
我失望的是看到我要嫁的男人
I was disappointed to see the man I was engaged to
从他的裤门里拽出一长条彩虹丝巾
pulling rainbow scarves out of his fly.
可你当时明明很高兴看到
But how delightful was it when I pulled out
丝巾最尾端连着的那束花啊
a bouquet at the end of those scarves?
所以等医生
It'll be the same thing
从你身体里拽出来个惊喜时  也是一样的
when the doctor pulls a beautiful surprise out of you.
所有人都说我插牛粪上了
Everyone said I could do better.
可你没听劝  转眼间
But you didn't listen, and presto change-o,
你怀上了小牛粪
my baby's inside you. Ta-da!
那是什么玩意儿
Ugh. What is that?
你为什么换边了
Why'd you switch sides?
本皇没落跑  你就跪谢吧
Be grateful I'm still in the room.
舒服吗
Comfy?
我很开心我不知道
Oh, I'm just happy I don't know
这些记忆海绵记忆过哪些"姿势"
what this memory foam remembers.
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
我知道我们说好了不交媾
I know we took coitus off the table,
但我想知道你怎么看待其他形式的亲密
but I was wondering how you feel about other forms of intimacy,
比如依偎睡觉
such as snuggling.
这个问题问得好
Well, it's funny you should ask,
因为我刚才还在琢磨
because I was wondering how you'd feel
你怎么看待用枕头墙把咱俩隔开这个主意
about separating the two of us with a pillow wall.
谢尔顿  我为你已经做出很多改变了
Sheldon, I've made more than enough accommodations for you.
我们都是大人了
We're both grown adults--
曾经也有过比这更亲密的举动
we've been far more intimate than this.
如果你不想依偎着睡  没问题
If you don't want to snuggle, fine--
但我不会搭一堵枕头墙的
but we're not building a pillow wall.
好啦  我道歉
Okay, well, I am sorry.
我只是担心我对温度的敏感
I'm just worried that my sensitivity to temperature
会让今夜很难熬
could make this a rough night.
没有恶意  可你屁股辐射出的热度
And no offense, but your bottom radiates enough heat,
不禁让我纳闷怎么美洲鬣蜥还没来取暖
I'm surprised there aren't iguanas lying on it.
到点了  谢尔顿睡觉时间到
That's it. It's Sheldon's bedtime.
他今晚在那睡定了
He is in for the night.
不敢相信  我们的公寓里就剩我们俩了
Wow. I cannot believe we are alone in our own apartment.
感觉很奇怪
It's weird.
孩子们离家去上大学后
This must be how parents feel
家长肯定就是这种感觉
when their kid goes off to college.
但如果家长觉得难过那就另当别论了
Unless they feel sad-- then it's different.
你想做什么
So, what do you want to do?
我太清楚我们要做什么了
I know exactly what we are gonna do.
不是吧  你是天才
Really? You're a genius,
想到的第一件事就是这个吗
and that's the first thing you come up with?
谢尔顿不在
Hey, Sheldon's not here,
所以我们要来点音乐嗨起来
so we are going to put on music
穿着内裤舞起来
and dance in our underwear.
好恶  直接做爱行吗
Ugh. Can we just have sex?
别担心
Oh, don't worry.
你见识我的曼妙舞姿后  一定会想扑倒我
Once you see my sweet moves, sex is inevitable.
你说"一定会扑倒"是吗
Inevitable, you say?
我让我的屁屁来回答你好了
I'll just let my hips do the talkin'.
不管了  我要打电话问清楚
Screw it. I'm calling and finding out.
好  打给他
Good. Call him.
慢着  我不确定我想知道
Wait, I'm not sure I want to know.
但你刚说了你想知道
But you just said you wanted to know.
现在我不知道我是否想知道
Well, now I don't know if I want to know!
喂
Hello?
再打给你
Call you back.
不  费曼博士
No, Dr. Feynman.
如果我帮你解决了  你怎么能学习呢
If I solve it for you, you'll never learn.
你在哪里学会的这些舞步啊
Wow! Where did you learn these moves?
这个世界也许已经遗忘了跳舞机
The world may have forgotten about Dance Dance Revolution,
但这个"犯罪高手"可没忘
but not this smooth criminal.
迈克尔·杰克逊名曲
MV里有他的招牌45度前倾动作
好了  你确定你想知道吗
Okay, you're positive you want to know?
-确定  -好的  我打了
- Yes. - Okay. Here we go.
响了
It's ringing.
喂
Hello?
-慢着  -打错了
- Wait. - Wrong number.
我跟你说了不要跳虫爬式[霹雳舞经典动作]
I told you not to do the worm.
你是对的
You were right.
喂
Hello.
老娘改主意了  挂掉  挂掉
I changed my mind! Hang up! Hang up!
-你在地上做什么  -稍等
- What are you doing down there? - Hang on.
你在打电话给谁
Who are you calling?
我浑身酸痛
I'm so sore.
我想我昨晚没睡超过两分钟
I don't think I slept two minutes last night.
爽啊  姐妹
Yeah, get it, girl.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
我觉得我拉伤了
I feel like I pulled something.
你为什么不叫我停下呢
Why didn't you tell me to stop?
更加不是你想的那样
Even more not what you think.
我不知道能否熬过和他一起住五周时间
I don't know if I can make it through five weeks living with him.
如果你需要甩开他一阵  火车模型店的老板
If you ever need a break, the owner of the train store
-会同意帮你照看他一下  让你去喝杯咖啡  -对
- will let you leave him there while you get a coffee. - Yeah.
早上好
Good morning.
看  我没敲门  不过没关系
See? I didn't knock, but it's fine.
我没敲门不过没关系  我没敲门不过没关系
I didn't knock, but it's fine. I didn't knock, but it's fine.
大家还好吗
So, how is everyone?
苦不堪言  精疲力尽
Miserable and exhausted.
是吗  我睡得可香了
Really? I slept great.
我没睡好  都怪你
Well, I didn't, and it's your fault.
这话怎么说  整个地板不都归你了吗
How? You had the whole floor to yourself.
谢尔顿  也许同居不是个好主意
Sheldon, maybe living together is a bad idea.
仅仅凭12小时的数据就得出结论
Well... Yeah, but what kind of scientists would we be,
我们算是哪门子的科学家
drawing a conclusion after only 12 hours of data?
昨晚差点用枕头闷死你的那种
The kind who almost put a pillow over your face last night.
我就知道我们间会出现问题
I anticipated we'd have problems,
但我真没想到你的科学严谨性会是其中之一
but I never thought your scientific rigor would be one of them.
打断下  你是在质疑我作为科学家的诚信吗
I'm sorry, are you questioning my integrity as a scientist?
实验室的一次性鞋套合脚吗
If the lab room disposable shoe cover fits.
这算是科学版撕逼吗
Was that a science diss?
-对  -这句撕得狠吗
- Yeah. - Was it a good one?
一个理论物理学家
What would a theoretical physicist
懂个屁的实验啊
understand about an experiment anyway?
就算混杂和变量同时扇你耳光
I mean, you wouldn't know a confounding variable
你都不会感觉到混杂变量
if two of them hit you in the face at the same time!
而且你根本听不懂笑点在哪里
And you don't even get that joke,
因为你根本没和混杂变量打过交道
'cause you don't even work with confounding variables!
你胆子够大的
How dare you?
我说了又怎么样
Oh, you heard me.
你的实验诚信度就是个笑话
Your experimental bona fides are laughable.
你居然敢取笑我的诚信度
Whoa, whoa! Now you're making fun of my bona fides?
是空集的东西要如何取笑
Can't make fun of something that's a null set.
-我感觉这句适合喊个"厉害"  -喊吧
- I feel like I should say "Damn." - Do it.
厉害
Damn!
如果你对科学方法的保护欲这么强
Well, if you are so protective of the scientific method,
也许我们应该用接下来五周时间
perhaps we should use the next five weeks
做完我们已经开始做的事
to finish what we started.
为了科学  也许我愿意
Well, for science, maybe I will!
为了科学  也许你应该这样做
For science, maybe you should!
-行  -行
- Fine! - Fine!
-很好  -好极了
- Good. - Great.
你想回我们公寓亲热吗
Do you want to go to our place and make out?
史蒂芬·霍金是坐电动轮椅溜达的吗
Does Stephen Hawking roll through the quad?
新邻居真是怪人
The new neighbors are weird.